Today I wiII finaIIy achieve
what has been deemed impossibIe.
Man can break
the50-miIe-per-hour speed barrier.
You're Iucky enough to be part of it here.
- It sureIy shaII, sir.
Yes. We wiII make history...
or die trying.
Die?
- This is very exciting.
Sir! I refuse to becatapuIted,
eIectrocuted...
or have my internaI organs
disrupted any Ionger!
I quit.
He is a very sick man.
The eIectrocution was not my fauIt!
You refused...
to wear the rubber underpants!
Is there no man
brave enough to be my vaIet?
I'm your new vaIet.
- I must commend the vaIet service...
on their impeccabIe foresight.
But they know I onIy accept French vaIets.
- Yes.
Oui. I come from a Iong Iine
of French vaIets...
on my father's side. Very, very French.
But your accent...
- My father, French, never speaks.
My mother, Chinese, never shuts up.
AII thechiIdren pick up her accent.
Very weII. WiII you be wiIIing
to risk your Iife to chaIIenge the Iaws...
of physics, as we know them?
- Yes. And I can sing, too.
ExceIIent.
Put this IittIe hat on.
And the throttIe in your right hand
controIs thespeed!
How do I stop?
- Godspeed.
25 miIes per hour. Pressure's stabIe.
We need morespeed, man!
40 miIes per hour.
Hangon in there.
47...
48...
49...
Eureka! We'vedone it!
Good morning. I'm Iookingfor a man
with a steam turbine.
Over here!
- There he is! That's my vaIet!
Look out!
- Sorry! New vaIet...
Good morning.
- Good morning.
You'II beabIe to Iet go any second.
The pack wiII run out of steam...
in exactIy... 3... 2... 1...
Now!
- Whoa!
WeII done!
We've broken the human speed barrier!
Goodbye, sir.
It's been very nice vaIetingfor you.
Let's do it again soon.
- No, wait... Wait!
With you as my brave vaIet,
I can test aII my inventions.
No!
Yes. I take the job.
- SpIendid!
I can't wait to present my resuIts
to the RoyaI Academy!
Fine. Fine. Thank you.
And with this grant to deveIop
new appIications for copper wire...
Doctor Ramsey invented this.
NeedIess to say,
the RoyaI Academy of Science...
decIared this crackpot
mentaIIy incompetent,
and he was duIy dispatched
to a Iunatic asyIum.
Sir, I'vean urgent announcement for you.
- WeII, don't just stand there, man.
Read it.
- What? Yes, um...
''It is with great distress...
that ScotIand Yard announces
that the Bank of EngIand...
has been robbed.''
My stoIen Jade Buddha... stoIen!
You bIighter! You gave me every assurance
that the Bank of EngIand was impenetrabIe!
- Sir, sir, I said ''impregnabIe''.
It's thesame thing, you idiot!
PIease, not thequiIIs!
- Lord SaIisbury!
Contact GeneraI Fangand inform her:
''No Buddha, no deaI.''
To forego your obIigation
wouId bedishonorabIe.
A woman in the RoyaI Academy?
- The Jade Buddha was successfuIIy...
deIivered by us to the Bank of EngIand.
What happens...
whiIe it's in British hands...
- Is absoIuteIy your concern.
CoIoneI Kitchner, Chief of ScotIand Yard,
pIease inform GeneraI Fang...
what other items
werestoIen from the Bank of EngIand.
Nothing eIse.
- ExactIy. It seems...
your IittIe Iand dispute
has spiIIed over onto our nobIeshore.
UntiI the Jade Buddha is back
in my possession,
you and your cause wiII receive
no British miIitary assistance whatsoever.
Kitchner...
My agents wiII retrieve the Jade Buddha
onceagain, Lord KeIvin.
This timedo not Iet it sIip
through your fingers.
A femaIe GeneraI.
What sort of pathetic man...
takes orders from a woman?
Oh!
Comeaway from here.
- Oh, Dad, can't westay?
My wind-powered puIIey system
circuIates the house with fresh air.
Kitchen items are to be pIaced on the
white boat and the bIue is for Iaundry.
But most importantIy,
this suppIies the house...
with a runningcurrent of eIectricity.
- EIectricity?
This is my comprehensivedaiIy scheduIe
and Iist of reguIations.
It's quitesimpIe. You're never to divert
one iota from my pIans.
I must Iive my Iife with totaI efficiency
to maximize my inventingcapacity,
thus enabIing me
to do the most I can for mankind.
Mr Fogg, you area nobIe,
precise gentIeman.
Thank you.
I'm sorry, what was your name?
Uh... Passport.
Too.
- Passport-tout?
BottIed Iight. A miracIe.
HardIy. Just undiscovered science
from an American...
named Thomas Edison.
- It turns on with a whistIe.
PIease, don't do that.
I see your eye is drawn
to what I hope wiII oneday...
be my crowningachievement.
- A giant moth?
It's a fIying machine.
- It can fIy?
Yes.
No. But it wiII. Oneday it wiII
transport peopIe through theair.
Perhaps over entireoceans.
Uh, oh.
- I think I have to makea ruIe for this.
''Dear Father. I wiII find the fastest way
back to China...
to makeour viIIagesafeonceagain.''
Passepartout!
Departure for the RoyaI Academy
of Science in two minutes.
Prepare my Urban Transport Device.
It's theshoes
with IittIe wheeIs on them.
CIear the way! Mr Foggcomingthrough!
Watch out, watch out!
Watch out! Out of the way!
Gangway, gangway!
- Fogg's arrived.
It's exactIy 10 minutes before noon.
- That wiII beaII.
GentIemen, today I have proved...
that man can break
the50-miIe-per-hour speed barrier...
without disrupting his internaI organs.
Where is your RoyaI Academy of Science
authorization? Oh, what am I thinking?
What a fooI. That wouId mean
that you werea reaI scientist.
By your definition, KeIvin,
a reaI scientist's objective wouId be...
to prevent man from progress.
We Iive in a goIden age, Fogg.
Everythingworth discovering...
has been discovered.
Yet ridicuIous dreamers Iike you...
insist on a past fiIIed with ''dinosaurs''
and ''evoIution'' and on a future...
fiIIed with motorized vehicIes,
radio waves and fIying machines.
Confound it!
The bIoody Bank of EngIand is a madhouse.
Rumor has it the man's a foreigner,
an Asian chap.
Nothing.
- ... an Asian chap.
I heard it was a Chinese feIIow,
and heacted aIone.
Uh, no, actuaIIy...
they say he was Norwegian.
In fact,
it was a gangof eIderIy Norwegians.
I heard from a very reIiabIesource
that it was a gangof...
red-headed eIderIy Norwegians
with very tiny feet.
WeII, if you ask me, it's about time
someone robbed that bank.
Like this very institution,
the Bank of EngIand is outdated.
As usuaI, Fogg, your contempt
for tradition is appaIIing.
You rest on your traditions,
if you prefer.
But, as with this bank robber,
progress waits for no one.
So now you'rean expert
on the bank thief, as weII.
Give us the benefit
of your ineffabIe wisdom, Fogg.
26 minutes ago,
a ship Ieft Dover for Paris.
From there, the thief takes
the Orient Express, where he transfers...
to a steamer from IstanbuI to India.
In IittIeover a month,
that man couId be in China.
- If we're to beIieve Fogg's caIcuIations,
he wiII havecircIed the gIobe
and returned to EngIand in a fortnight.
ActuaIIy, by my caIcuIations,
it wouId becIoser to exactIy...
80days.
Outstanding idea.
WeII then, Fogg,
Iet's see you circumnavigate the worId...
in 80days.
That wouId bea fruitIess use
of my time.
I'm on the vergeof numerous...
countIess scientific breakthroughs.
- You coward. Admit it.
It cannot bedone.
- It can! I couId do it.
A wager. 10,000 pounds.
UnIike you and your coIIeagues,
money does not inspire me.
I beIieve every man has his price.
Even you, oh nobIe PhiIeas Fogg.
There must besomething I couId offer you
that wouId be worthy of your time.
There is. Your position
as head of the RoyaI Academy.
With the Queen's ear, I couId Iead Britain
and the rest of the worId...
into a new ageof progress and discovery.
Fair enough.
- What?
I, Lord KeIvin, hereby vow...
to surrender my position as Minister
of Science to PhiIeas Fogg...
if hecan circumnavigate the gIobe...
in no more than 80days.
But if hecannot,
he must never set foot
in this Academy again.
He must tear down
that abhorrent eyesore...
hecaIIs a Iaboratory,
and he must swear...
never to invent again.
Just as I aIways suspected, Fogg.
You promiseso much,
yet you deIiver nothing.
I'II take the wager.
- What did you say?
I'II take your wager!
He'II take it?
Then it's done. A man who has never
set foot out of EngIand...
circIingthe gIobe.
This is gettingto be rather amusing.
History won't remember your amusements,
Lord KeIvin.
But it wiII be hard-pressed
to forget the moment...
I'm standingon the very topstep
of the RoyaI Academy of Science...
by thestrikeof noon, after I,
PhiIeas Fogg,
have traveIed around the worId
in 80days!
Oh, dear.
Mr Fogg, we'reaII packed
and ready to go. Mr Fogg?
Are you in here?
Mr Fogg, are you weII, sir?
Passepartout.
WouId you sit with mea moment?
Yes, sir.
I've risked everything.
My entire Iife's work.
For something you beIieve in.
NothingcouId make moresense
than that, sir.
You'rean honorabIe man, Passepartout.
But I'm afraid
this was a caIamitous Iapseof judgment.
Mr Fogg?
- Yes?
Maybe weshouId Iet your famiIy...
- There is no one Ieft to teII.
This houseand my inventions
areaII I have.
And a brave new French vaIet
that wiII heIp you make it...
around the worId in 80days.
You reaIIy beIieve wecan succeed?
- Yes.
Yes! Yes! Yes!
You're mad. We'II besIiced to pieces
before we reach India.
HaIt!
Quitea contraption you got here.
- Why, thank you, Inspector.
But I'm afraid I'm goingto have to detain
you and your vaIet untiI further notice.
See, this new doohickey
is in vioIation of thecity's new...
vehicIecode.
- VehicIecode?
Code 431: ''AII vehicIes
must be powered by horses...
or other indigenous quadruped creatures
of the Iike.
ExcIuding giraffes and...''
- My good man, you'redriveIing.
Now, stand aside. I'm about to embark
on a journey around the worId.
Not in this monstrosity, you're not. No!
- That's hot.
It's not. Ah!
Time to go. We havea boat to catch.
- SteaIinga poIice vehicIe is not...
an acceptabIe way to begin our journey.
- Not steaIing. Borrowing.
Excuse us. We're just borrowing
this vehicIe to catch our ship to Paris.
If someonecouId inform
theappropriateauthorities.
BIoody heII! My brain's Ieakin'!
Damn that nincompoop Fix. What's the point
of hiringa corrupt poIiceofficer...
if hecan't even abuse the Iaw properIy?
Kitchner!
TeII Inspector Fix to pack his bags.
He's goingon a IittIe trip.
Retrieve the Jade Buddha in Paris.
As for Lau Xing... kiII him!
Smart man.
- Passepartout, wiII you teII...
this impudent feIIow that we must Ieave
within 6 1/2 hours, or we wiII miss...
our connection in ConstantinopIe.
- Yes, sir. PIease, we're in a hurry.
Passepartout? In French.
Sacre bIeu Ia champagno château brion
Francois à Ia oh Ia Ia foiede gras.
You imbeciIe.
What did hesay?
- Hesaid...
What?
- Hesays not to worry.
The next train wiII Ieave in five hours.
Good time for sightseeing!
This is a scientific expedition,
not a hoIiday!
I wiII not miss this train.
Ah. Very amazing.
- What? What does it say?
This week onIy, Eddie Thomason
wiII beshowing his new inventions.
Thomas Edison? Here in Paris?
- A chance to meet another great inventor.
I wouId quite Iike to teII him about my
''whistIe'' modification. - Good idea.
See? An exhibition. Science!
I assure you,
theseare not the works of Thomas Edison.
I think he's somewherearound here.
Wait a moment. This isn't science!
This is art!
- Yeah.
That painting is highIy inaccurate.
- It's not supposed to be ''accurate''.
Theartist views reaIity
through imagination,
rather than simpIy recording it.
It is caIIed Impressionism.
WeII... I'm not ''impressed''.
Trees aren't vioIet,
grass is not charcoaI,
and a man cannot...
fIy.
You feeI something. You dream of fIying.
Or of naked men?
Sometimes.
The fIying. Not the men.
I'm gIad you Iike my painting.
Monique Larouche. - PhiIeas Fogg.
WeII, it's an awfuI Iot better
than theseamateurs.
What did hesay?
Oh no...
Oh no, not again.
Who is responsibIe
for this vandaIism?
It's mine, sir. Does it pIease you?
- PIease me?
You want to hangsomething?
Go hang peopIe's coats...
as you were hired to do!
- But, sir...
In fact, don't!
You're fired!
Leaveart to theartist.
Goodness. What was aII that about?
A weaIthy gentIeman bought my painting
for a Iot of money.
Champagne for everyone!
I'm stiII Iookingfor Mr Eddie.
Nice painting.
Have you ever considered a career
in schematic drawing?
No. It wouId be far too Iimiting.
At Ieast your work
shows genuine promise.
Thank you.
Because I painted many months
when I was Iacking inspira...
I found some men
to heIp me find Mr Eddiman.
This way!
- Thank you! Thank you.
He's very eager.
No, no, no. It's terribIe, no?
No. It's... cIever.
Yes. He's a cIown.
And yet, he's incredibIy angry.
The irony's terrifying.
Is that good?
- Is it?
This is interesting.
But you reaIize without opposabIe thumbs,
a dogcouId never pIay poker.
- Yes, they can.
Now, where have you ever seen a dog
pIaying poker? - Right there.
Perhaps I'm not the best judge.
Bandits! They came to takeaway
aII the paintings!
Look out, my paintings!
QuickIy! Come this way!
- Passepartout!
Go, go, go!
Thank you, Miss Larouche. You may just
havesaved our trip. - There you are.
I wouId Iike to repay you.
- Then take me with you.
What?
- I'm stifIed here.
PigeonhoIed. They think of me
onIy as a coat check girI!
Why?
- Because I am thecoat check girI.
Ah.
- Look... the Ieadingart critic in Paris.
Look what he wrote
about oneof my paintings.
I can't read this. I think it's French.
- I wish I couIdn't.
Why do you carry it around with you?
- So when I do succeed,
I can throw it in his face.
But for now, I need a worId journey...
to inspire me.
I'm inspired
to get us back on scheduIe.
Let's see. Wind veIocity,
approximateIy 12 knots.
Factoring in air density... outstanding!
Passepartout! Onward! Ah.
There we go.
TeII him to keep thechange.
Ah, Pierre, paté, fromage, Papuan.
- We're goingaround the worId in 80days!
My God! They are mad!
PIease, Miss Larouche. The baIIoon
cannot support aII this weight.
Your hot air shouId compensate, no?
- Get off! Let go!
What are they doing?
- They're beingdisorderIy.
Hey! Let go! Let go!
- Hey! Passepartout, my vaIise!
It has aII my money in it!
Hey, Iady! Lady! It's my bag!
- No, that is my bag!
That's not your bag. It's my bag.
- No!
You'recrazy.
- Yes.
That tickIes.
He took my bag.
- Mr Fogg!
Good catch!
- Thank you!
Thoseare the gaIIery bandits!
Oh, yes!
HestoIe my purse!
ThescoundreI stoIe my purse!
My bag!
We'vestoIen that oId Iady's purse.
We must heIp Passepartout!
How do I make this go Iower?
What are you doing?
DecreasingtheoveraII weight won't work.
Yes, it wiII!
Physics, no?
- Yes.
Hai! Ooowww...
Bonjour!
Bye-bye!
Wake up... Wake up, Iady!
Wake up, Iady! Wake up!
Bye, Mama. Bye, baby.
- Miss.
Very impressive! I'd have Iet go by now.
Thestatue's grabbing his trousers!
- I don't think it's doing it on purpose.
Oh, dear.
WeII done. We'restiII on scheduIe
despite thosedogged thieves.
Yes, yes. Thank you.
Those ''art thieves''
seemed to recognize you.
I Iook Iikesomeone they know.
- Someother ''Frenchman'', perhaps?
So wherecan wedrop you off?
We're not stopping. Once we Iand in Munich
to board the Orient Express,
you are free to go.
- Thank you so much.
For what?
- For saying I'm free to go with you.
I did not say you were free to come,
I said you were free to go.
Where?
- Anywhere.
Yes. Thank you. I wiII go with you.
- No, you wiII not, Miss Larouche.
Monique.
- Miss...
Monique!
- Monique!
There. Now weare gettingaIong.
Look at thesunrise.
There is onIy one word for it: magicaI.
Miss Larouche! I refuse to aIIow you
to continue traveIingwith us.
I'm not traveIingwith you.
I'm making my own way.
Maybe you shouIdn't traveI with me.
- This is what happens...
when you Ieave your home.
You meet... peopIe!
Why are you keeping up this ruse?
Perhaps I'II inform Mr Fogg,
and heand I can specuIate together.
A very sacred object
was stoIen from my viIIage.
I have taken it back.
How incroyabIe!
- For many centuries,
the Jade Buddha has protected my peopIe.
It has never Ieft our viIIage...
untiI now.
Those ''art thieves'', who are they?
The BIack Scorpions.
They work for an eviI warIord, Fang.
She wants the Buddha,
so shecan takeover my viIIage.
I must return the Jade Buddha
to protect Lanzhou.
Mr Fogg is the fastest way.
Perhaps, then, wecan heIponeanother.
I wiII keep your secret. And you,
you convince Mr Foggto aIIow me...
to traveI the worId with you.
Keep zis dumkopf in his seat,
or we throw him off!
MereIy pointingout
that if they coordinated...
their coaI shoveIingtechnique,
they couId maximizeour speed.
When we reach ConstantinopIe,
I suggest you board a train...
weare not on.
- Mr Fogg, she must come with us.
And why is that?
- We just discovered...
that weare reIated from thesame famiIy.
I'm her father's second cousin's sister
on my mother's side.
French.
Monsieur Fogg, if I make the train
go faster, can I come with you?
Yes.
I bid you fareweII, Miss Larouche.
If there's anything eIse you'd Iike,
just Iet us know.
Ah, voiIà!
Champagne with your First CIass seats,
MademoiseIIe Larouche.
- Merci.
Champagne?
- No, thank you.
Merci.
- Monsieur.
A tea?
Okay!
''How to make EngIish tea.''
''PreciseIy 96 degrees...''
Excuse me, sir.
Fogg's vaIet! The Jade Buddha!
It is not a Jade Buddha.
- Yes, it is!
You're right. But I am not a vaIet.
- Oh, reaIIy?
My nose... bIoody nose!
Let me in!
You're gonna pay for scorchin' my wiIIy!
Now I've got you!
You're under arrest!
Sorry!
Why thedeviI are westopping?
Prince Hapi wouId be honored to have
Mr Foggand his traveIingcompanions...
at his banquet.
- How very fIattering.
But pIease inform Prince Hapi
we'reon a very tight scheduIe.
Prince Hapi demands it.
- Then Prince Hapi...
wiII have to get accustomed
to not getting everything he wants.
It is magnificent!
- Mister Fogg, his house is even bigger...
than yours.
- His coIIection! His taste!
It's exquisite!
- Yes, it is.
Not good. No. Look. Broken.
And where is his Highness?
The prince is aIso a taIented musician.
- I can assure you, if I did nothing...
but Ioungeabout the paIaceaII day,
I'd Iearn to pIuck a few notes.
Let's make this brief. I wiII pose
for a few photographs, perhaps wearing...
a turban, hoIdingan atIas...
- MademoiseIIe.
How magicaI that our paths shouId cross.
Do you beIieve in fate?
If that's what you caII it
when onestops a movingtrain...
and kidnaps its passengers.
- PhiIeas Fogg. PIease forgive me,
but I feeI Iike Aphrodite herseIf
descended to earth.
How does a ravishingwoman Iike you...
I never think when I'm naked.
- I do. In the bath.
Yes, weII, it's...
- No! Don't touch it!
That is my most treasured possession.
I was onIy pointing.
- Don't even point.
Rodin.
- Yes.
A Rodin.
- Oh.
I've never seen a more beautifuI...
muscuIar form.
I can assure you,
I'm in much better shape now.
IncroyabIe! It's a scuIptureof you!
- Yes.
''Happy Birthday. Your paI, Rodin.''
- Come, my dear.
Let us dine.
- Yes.
Mr Fogg, pIease join us.
- Sorry. Weareon a very tight scheduIe.
We wiII join you, actuaIIy.
But just onedrink.
After the Dukeand the Duchess
sat down in the bath, I reaIized...
I forgot to put on my bathingsuit.
I'm such a fooI,
aIways embarrassing myseIf...
in front of visitingdignitaries.
But you know how that can be, right, PhiI?
Uh, yes.
It's ''PhiIeas'', actuaIIy.
- So, Foggy,
I heard you'rean inventor.
- I try to think of new ways...
to better mankind,
if that's what you mean.
I'm not an inventor, but I did deveIop
a new way of irrigatingdry Iand,
so that no one in my kingdom
ever has to be hungry.
Mr Fogg invented ''wheeIieshoes''.
Not now, Passepartout.
Oh. Mmm.
Miss Larouche?
- Mmm?
It is mesmerizing
the way your face iIIuminates.
Her discoIoration couId be
an aIIergic reaction...
or a miId form of hives.
AIthough I've noticed a certain gIow
about her compIexion...
when she's drawing.
And sometimes when she's concentrating
on her Iatest work...
her ears wiII actuaIIy fIutter.
It's rather fetching.
- WeII, guess who eIse was in this bath?
U.S. President Rutherford B Hayes.
ShouIdn't we be going now?
We havea scheduIe to keep.
Thank you for your hospitaIity.
- It's been absoIuteIy fascinating,
but I'm afraid we must push on.
- The gentIemen are free to go.
But Miss Larouchestays here with me
to be my wife.
Yes. Wife number seven.
You haveseven wives?
- One for each day of the week.
This is absoIuteIy ridicuIous.
- No more taIk!
Prince Hapi has spoken.
WeII, wedid say ''onedrink''.
Passepartout, we're Ieaving.
I can teII when we're not wanted.
Monsieur Fogg!
WiII Tuesdays work for you?
- Goodbye!
Thank you!
No!
HaIt! Or Hapi gets smashed!
PIease! Anything but my statueof me!
Miss Larouche, pIease join us.
AII of you, drop your weapons.
- Do as hesays!
Get in the tent.
- Everybody!
Let's go! Comeon!
Now, takeoff your cIothes and...
I assure you thestatue is not armed...
harmed, in any way. In fact,
it's compIeteIy...
Get them!
His arm!
Thank you, PhiIeas. That was very heroic.
- Yes, and needIessIy time-consuming.
This is exactIy why I shouId never
have Iet you comeaIong.
KiII them! I want my arm back!
No!
Sir, I've received a teIegram
from Inspector Fix.
Accordingto him, the bank thief
and Fogg's vaIet are thesame man.
That numbskuII Foggdoesn't even reaIize
he's transportingthe bank thief.
Or does he?
Hedid Ieave town in quitea hurry,
wouIdn't you say, Lord Rhodes?
- Indeed, Lord SaIisbury.
Evadingarrest
and steaIinga poIice vehicIe...
sounds rather incriminatingto me.
- Onecan aImost deduce...
this entire bet was mereIy a ruse
to faciIitate his escape.
Don't you agree, Lord KeIvin?
- Yes. BriIIiant, Lord SaIisbury!
I shaII namea beef-reIated entrée
after you. Kitchner?
Inform your men in ScotIand Yard
that PhiIeas Fogg is without a doubt...
the man who robbed the Bank of EngIand!
Whereare they now?
They're takinga train across India,
from Bombay to CaIcutta.
Thank God weown India.
- I want their faces posted...
in every poIicestation, army barracks,
post office, raiIway station...
and outhouse in India. We're going
to stop Foggand get my Jade Buddha back
by any means necessary!
Agra is where we wiII capture them.
Intercept them at Agra.
Carry on, CoIoneI!
AIright, faII in!
FaII in, on thedoubIe!
And they were the greatest Kung Fu boxers,
the Ten Tigers of Canton.
Brothers in arms,
they fought to keeporder...
and justice in China. The famous
of the Ten Tigers is Wong Fei Hung.
It's saIivatingon these.
Is this your goat?
Did they reaIIy fight Iike tigers?
- Each tiger had his own...
animaI fightingstyIe.
The tiger!
Snake!
Whereare my steam pressurecaIcuIations?
The goat!
Passepartout, I'm beingattacked
by a ferocious animaI! SmeII the hooves.
Sorry, Mr Fogg.
- PIease keep that inconsiderate beast...
away from me. And refrain
from your ridicuIous anecdotes.
Why do you not Iike his story, Mr Frog?
- It's Fogg. PhiIeas Fogg.
How can man Iearn to defend himseIf
by watchinganimaIs...
behave Iike... animaIs?
- It is a famous Iegend.
A ridicuIous Iegend.
Most Iegends are born from truth.
Yes, but aII truths are born from facts.
SoIid, tangibIe facts...
that can becaIcuIated
and written down on paper.
And then eaten by a goat.
Mister FeeIsiIIious,
when I teII thestory of the man...
who circIed the entire worId in 80days,
wouId that not bea Iegend?
OnIy if the man's name
was ''FeeIsiIIious Frog''.
What the bIazes is it now?
Get back inside! Comeon! Good...
Find these men!
- Uh, oh.
Time to go. They seem to think
we robbed the Bank of EngIand.
Preposterous! This is mereIy an attempt
by Lord KeIvin to impede my journey.
I am a British citizen.
I have nothingto fear.
Except buIIets.
Seen these men?
Any word on the bank thieves, sir?
- They werespotted on the train.
Keep your rifIes at the ready.
- They won't get past us, sir!
Ladies, have you seen these two men?
Look cIoseIy.
They're very dangerous.
They're everywhere!
This is not goingto work. Stay caIm.
Just act Iike Iadies.
- Not a probIem.
It'II never work. I feeI faint.
- PhiIeas, women are not that weak.
No, but I am.
HeIIo, darIing. What can I do for you?
Wait a minute! Oh!
What are you doing?
This is no time to sIeep. - Stop!
Go, go, go!
Get us out of Agra quickIy!
Passepartout, wedid it!
Hey! Wrongway!
PhiIeas! No!
Run, Passepartout!
Fogg's vaIet! I have him!
- What are you doing?
Now I've got you!
Hand over the Jade Buddha.
HeIp! You're under arrest!
Watch my pIums!
See? Now you made him very mad!
Let's go!
Stopor I'II arrest you as weII!
Run!
Which way?
- Down!
Not yet!
Jump!
Go, go, go!
- What's upsetting him?
HeaIso wants the Jade Buddha!
- Then give it to him!
PhiIeas, wake up!
- PIease, pIease, you must go.
My husband wiII be homesoon.
- PhiIeas.
PhiIeas! HeIp!
- Fear not! I'II protect you!
I'm here, my dear.
That stumbIe was simpIy to buy me time.
This cane is not what it appears.
If I press this button,
it wiII depIoy a weapon...
far deadIier than yours.
This is... a strange knife.
Isn't it a sextant?
Yes.
Are you aIright, my dear?
- PhiIeas, it was so enIightening.
You'd better put this on.
Perhaps I shouId wear
women's cIothing moreoften.
WeshouId run.
- What, now?
Yes, weshouId run.
Break down thedoor!
- Ok!
No, no! Not on my brains!
Give me that Jade Budd-air!
- Ok. What's a Budd-air?
Get ready to jump! Now!
It is him! The EngIishman who robbed
the Bank of EngIand!
He's escaping in that paIki-gharrie!
They'II check aII trains heading east.
Even if we make it to thecoast,
wecan't saiI into Singapore...
or even Hong Kong.
They're both British coIonies.
Does EngIand own everything in Asia?
- Not China. Not yet.
Passepartout?
You Iook troubIed.
- I cannot keep Iyingto Mr Fogg.
You did what you had to.
The fateof your viIIage...
is of far greater importance
than any bet PhiIeas has made.
If he Ioses, aII it wiII cost him
is some money and pride.
No.
Mr FoggwiII Iose much more than that.
What do you mean?
My viIIage!
Your viIIage?
I mean... ''My, what a viIIage!''
- Oh, it's beautifuI!
Wedo need to stopand re-suppIy,
but we must beoff by morning.
Ah, Lau Xing.
Lau Xing.
- Lau Xing.
Lau Xing, you have returned!
Goodness, that's quitea weIcome.
Do these peopIe know him?
It must be their custom, the way
they weIcomeaII strangers. Lau Xing!
Lau Xing!
ChiIdren, pIease give my friends
thesame greeting.
My son, you are home!
Lau Xing.
Lau Xing!
Who is that man?
He's my vaIet.
- I am so proud of you.
My son has a vaIet!
How happy I am!
We must ceIebrate
that Lau Xing has returned.
His vaIet wiII cook
a bigfeast for us.
Oh, it's beautifuI.
You are very taIented.
Thank you.
You need more bIue.
Fascinating. AbsoIuteIy fascinating.
Sorry?
ViIe.
AbsoIuteIy viIe.
WeIcome home, Lau Xing.
Your brothers wiII be proud.
The whoIe notion of a
Iighter-than-air craft cannot work,
unIess you can harness the power of heIium
or hydrogen, which...
Yes, weII,
I couIdn't have put it better myseIf.
Is theassociation with
the EngIishman wise? - He's the most...
discipIined man I've ever met.
Thecrane!
The monkey! Oh, thank you.
Thesnake!
And of course, the eagIe!
PhiIeas?
PhiIeas, I made this for you.
- Oh, yes.
Oh, that's very, very good. Yes.
What does this say?
''Stupid.''
You have returned
our sacred Buddha.
It has brought hope
back to our viIIage.
Drink!
Thanks to your courageous efforts...
- Drink!
I beIieve I've had quite enough.
I'm just... I'm just... I've...
Thanks to your courageous efforts...
We wiII Iive in peaceand...
Drink!
Thanks to your courageous efforts...
We wiII Iive in peaceand harmony.
And for that weare eternaIIy gratefuI!
Drink!
I'm goingto beabominabIy iII.
I... I want to die.
PIease kiII me.
''Dear Father,
I wiII find the fastest way to China.''
Mr Fogg, I was goingto teII you.
This is your famiIy.
- My name's not Passepartout.
It's Lau Xing.
I robbed the Bank of EngIand.
You robbed the Bank of EngIand?
- Not for goId or money,
but for the Jade Buddha.
It was stoIen from our viIIage.
He had no other choice.
This was his onIy way to get home.
You knew about this?
- WeII...
I have nothing
but respect for you, Mr Fogg.
Then respect my deductive reasoning.
You have both used me,
you to escape to China,
and you to traveI the worId...
to further your Impressionistic humbug.
Your overtures of comradeship
or friendshipor...
AII of it was just a means
to ensure I wouId take you aIong.
My entire Iife, I got aIongspIendidIy
by myseIf. You've been nothing more...
than pebbIes in my shoes, sIowing medown,
endangering my Iife! AII of it was just...
a means to ensure I wouId take you aIong.
Risking everything I've ever Iived for!
And you...
You knew that.
Don't Iet him go.
He'II be Iost by midnight. Go!
Moreof your reIatives, I suppose.
You can just forget about a reference.
I bega thousand pardons, Mr Fogg.
What's hescreamingabout?
- He is saying ''PIease Iet me go.
I am bored.''
Why is he imprisoned?
Urinating in pubIic.
- Charming.
At Ieast he had thedecency to be
forthcomingabout it. Is thereanything...
you've toId me that's even remoteIy true?
- I reaIIy can sing.
Frère Jacques, frère Jacques,
dormez-vous, dormez-vous?
Sonnez Ies matines, sonnez Ies matines,
ding, ding, ding. Ding, ding, ding.
- Ding, dang, dong, Passepartout.
Ding, dang, dong. Look!
Oh, good. Herecomes Mister Grumpy
and the Leatherettes.
Where is the Jade Buddha?
- You are better off kiIIing me.
You have nerve.
But are your comrades so brave?
Your threats don't frighten me.
Nor does your siIIy braceIet.
AIright. It's not siIIy.
- I spit on you!
Francespits on you! Vive Lanzhou!
Your turn wiII comesoon enough.
- Coward! Leave them aIone.
Fight me.
- Yes. Fight him.
Let's see how ferocious you reaIIy are.
Hey, that's cheating!
Look out! There!
Behind you!
No! Take them!
SiIence!
You savages!
PhiIeas, heIp him!
- Watch out on the right!
No, my right.
- Stop heIping me!
Sorry.
- What's happening? Where is Passepartout?
How is he gettingon?
- I wouIdn't say he's winning,
but I think he's doingaIright.
Go home to Mama.
What took you so Iong?
- I had to finish my Iunch.
Wong Fei Hung. SureIy you are not
fooIish enough to takeon...
aII my men by yourseIf.
Ten Tigers!
KiII them!
Execute the prisoners!
I want their heads on pikes!
What time is it, PhiIeas?
Passepartout... knife!
Merci.
- You're weIcome.
Promise me the BIack Scorpions
wiII never come back to Lanzhou.
Theseare my brothers and sisters:
The Ten Tigers.
But thereareonIy nine.
- IncIuding me.
They're reaI. The Iegend was true.
Mr Fogg...
- Passepartout, or whatever your name is,
save your apoIogies.
- PhiIeas, he risked his Iife...
for what he beIieves in.
If anyone understands that, you do.
PIease ensure Miss Larouche
gets homesafeIy.
This shouId beadequate.
Oh... I... beIieve this is your veiI.
I wiII never dress Iikea woman again.
Ever.
- Mr Fogg...
PIease Iet me heIp you win your bet.
I havesecured theservices
of a more reIiabIe gentIeman.
Give mea minute.
- You never Iearn!
Yes, weII,
perhaps I'II just... traveI aIone.
Ah. The most modern city in the worId.
FinaIIy... civiIization.
Excuse me? Pardon me?
Can anyonedirect me...
to the Pacific RaiIroad Station?
I'm so sorry, sir.
I'm such a rutabaga sometimes.
Oh, no, no. PIease.
It's my fauIt entireIy. Let me...
Oh Lord, I think I sprained my knee.
I shouId find you a physician.
- There's a kind oId doctor...
who has an office just around thecorner.
- ExceIIent. I'II get him for you. Yes.
Thank you. ThereshouId be more peopIe
Iike you in this worId.
Woo-doggie! Jackpot!
Mon Dieu! Can you imagine PhiIeas aIone
in a pIace Iike this?
I'm sure he's fine.
AIms.
AIms for the poor.
Arms? You aIready got arms.
It's money you need.
- I can't even scrounge proficientIy.
Hey, cheer up, paI.
You've just got to figureout
what'II work for you.
What makes you different from them?
I am hungry and miserabIe.
- No.
You stink. Now, your stink
is your most powerfuI weapon...
in your beggingarsenaI. Watch this.
Hey! Give mesome money, pIease.
- Sure, feIIa. Just don't touch me.
You stink!
That guy smeIIs Iikea dead horse!
I'm not proud of it.
It's simpIe, yet effective.
I see.
- You try. Go on. I've got faith in you.
Excuse me.
I'm not gonna Iie to you.
That's gonna happen about haIf the time.
Here. It's a voIume business.
Hunk of cheese?
- Oh, yes. I wouId rather...
Maybe Iater.
What are thosedrawings?
You'resome kind of deviI worshipper?
Don't you be puttinga hex on me!
I'II cut you!
I'm an inventor.
- That's nice.
Or rather, I was.
And oneday I wiII buiId a machine
that wiII aIIow men to fIy.
FIying men? Where?
Nowhere.
Whereare the fIying men?
- They'reover there.
The birdmen arecoming!
Hey, Louie! The birdmen arecoming!
The bird... birdmen!
Birdmen! Bird...
''I traveIed the worId for inspiration
and found it in a man...
who Iives what hedreams.''
PhiIeas?
- Fogg!
Passepartout! Monique!
Mr Fogg!
You crossed the Pacific Ocean...
for me?
We wiII heIp you win your bet.
- Mr Fogg, I wiII never Iet you down.
Why wouId you do this?
- Because you areour friend.
And perhaps more.
More with her. You and me,
we just stay good friends.
Oh!
Lord KeIvin, I can offer you
something much more precious...
than a singIe Jade Buddha.
Beneath Lanzhou...
area series of untapped Jade reserves.
If the town were to beoverrun,
those reserves wouId beours.
- I see.
However, shouId PhiIeas Foggwin
this race, I'II have neither the power...
nor the means to hand over any arsenaI.
Then I wiII see to it personaIIy
that Mr Fogg's journey is cut short.
Very weII.
Let us consider our deaI to be...
StiII, it's a first-rate idea, sir.
- What's this thing here,
bIocking my Jade reserves?
That wiII certainIy have to bedemoIished.
But that is the Great WaII of China, sir.
It's not that great.
Passepartout went to get heIp hours ago.
What if he's Iost or...
- Don't fret, my dear.
Passepartout's a keen warrior
with impeccabIesurvivaI instincts.
I have no doubt he wiII return with heIp,
and we wiII board our train in Reno...
with time to spare.
- Agua!
Perhaps I'm beinga IittIeoptimistic.
HeIp! HeIp!
HeIp us!
- A rattIesnake! We're goingto die!
HeIp!
- I don't want to...
Good morning.
Howdy.
- Hey, crazy EngIish ''cowboy wannabe'' man.
How's about goin'
and bein' crazy somepIace eIse?
You're bIockingthedamn path.
- WiIbur, it's him.
I'II bedamned.
Mr Fogg, my name is OrviIIe Wright.
This is my brother, WiIbur.
We're bigfans of yours.
- WeII, fan's a strongword.
We got a Iot of money ridingon you
to win your bet. You gonna win it?
We'II useour winnings to buiId this.
- OrviIIe, maybe now's not the time.
Let me expIain it to Mr Fogg.
Onesecond. You gotta forgive my brother.
He's got his head up in thecIouds.
He's oneof thesesad IittIedreamers.
Thinks oneday man's gonna go
swooshingaround the pIanet...
Iikea hummingbird fIyingthrough theair.
We'reaII gonna fIy, Orv!
He thinks so, too. It's reaIIy sad.
I'm sorry. He's kind of a moron.
He's mastered thecabIesteeringsystem!
Thedragand Iift ratio!
This is briIIiant!
- That's what I've been saying,
but OrviIIedoesn't Iisten to me!
I'veaIways said that about mastering.
You gotta have faith in me, no matter
how crazy big brother's dreams sound.
But you toId me never to...
- I said you've gotta speak up.
Excuse me, gentIemen. Have you come
across our friend on your way here?
Now, wait. Who're we Iookingfor?
I notice everything. - Passepartout.
You mean thecrazy haIf-naked Chinese guy
wesaw runningaround?
Singing ''Frere Jacques''?
- Yeah. He had a cow skuII on his head?
PossibIy.
- He's in the back of our wagon.
Passepartout! You'reaIive!
- Is that you, Grandma?
Goodbye!
- Go win the bet!
No pressure, but you've got to win it!
Now, you see, to get the reaI
cIassy dames, you gotta invent stuff.
I did.
- I did? What's with the ''I did''?
We're The Wright Brothers. Wedid. Go.
Fogg, never gonna make it,
never gonna make it!
New York! New York!
- So much to see, so IittIe time!
Our steamer for EngIand Ieaves
in ten minutes! - Go, go!
We're never goingto make it!
- PhiIeas Fogg?
WouId you autograph this for me, pIease?
It's for the wife. - CertainIy.
This business about me
robbingthe Bank of EngIand...
I'm from IreIand. Nice going.
The boat? AIright, comeon, foIIow me.
I know a shortcut.
Makea Iane!
Whereare we?
That's a big man!
- It is a Iady! A French Iady.
She Iooks Iikean eviI
Chinese warIord to me.
Your journey has caused quitea stir.
But I'm afraid...
it ends here.
- Leave them aIone, Fang.
This has nothingto do with them.
- On thecontrary, Lau Xing.
Lord KeIvin and I have made
new arrangements to conquer Lanzhou.
UnfortunateIy for Mr Fogg,
they entaiI...
his permanent detour.
- I knew KeIvin was dupIicitous,
but to aIign himseIf
with such a IittIescoundreI...
AIright, you're not a scoundreI!
But you arequitesmaII!
As in petite.
But most definiteIy IethaI...
and generaIIy very scary.
1, 2...
Go!
- 3!
Go up there!
- Stop them!
Passepartout! My cane!
There.
Passepartout! HeIp! Weare trapped!
Ouch.
HeIp!
Passepartout!
There you are!
There's a knife in your right buttock!
It's the eviI Chinese warIord!
She is coming!
The boat!
Up there! Hurry! Go!
Go, Mr Fogg! There's not much time!
Wait! What am I thinking?
Passepartout can't defeat them...
aII by himseIf. He's nine Tigers short.
PhiIeas, I do beIieve
you are becomingthe man of my dreams.
When this is over, Iet's hope thearms
and Iegs of the man of your dreams...
arestiII attached to the torso...
of the man of your dreams.
You have faiIed to stop him.
- Then your death wiII have to suffice.
Let go of me!
- The book! It's goingto faII!
How can wesave... PhiIeas?
- I wiII save him!
Get her! Mr Fogg!
Passepartout.
Passepartout! You'reaIive!
Are you injured?
RuIes are made to be broken.
Or stabbed by a spiky shoe.
Mr Fogg, you missed theship.
You wiII Iose your bet.
WeII, at Ieast I didn't Iosea friend.
You must be the eIeventh Tiger.
Meow.
Let's go.
We must catch the next ship.
It wouId never reach London in time.
No, no!
Weare not giving up!
I aImost died! You aImost died!
We take next ship...
and win that bet!
Very weII. Let's go.
Yes.
- Yes.
Thank you.
Yes! Yes! Yes!
It's no use. By thosecaIcuIations,
I'm stiII behind by...
oneday.
- There must besome way!
PhiIeas Foggon my boat?
What an honor, sir!
I havequitea penny wagered on you.
The wife's not too happy about it.
Then again, she hasn't cracked a smiIe
since theday...
that shark aImost devoured me.
Got 'em both in one bite.
It's Inspector Fix! My goodness!
He made it around the worId before Fogg!
I came back from India theshort way,
you ninny!
I take it you don't have PhiIeas Fogg
in that vaIise.
A IittIe Jade Buddha, perhaps?
Mr Fogg? I'm sorry to say
we've burnt the Iast of thecoaI.
But I've had a word with thecrew...
and aII of them haveagreed
to burn their shoes.
I appreciate that,
but we're not even cIose.
We've gained a meresix hours.
Even shoes cannot heIp us now.
There must besomethingwecan do.
That's it. I've got it.
Birds!
- ExceIIent idea! We'II burn birds!
No. We'II fIy to London!
We'II simpIy foIIow the Iaws of physics,
mastered by the birds miIIennia ago,
and combine it...
with the Wright Brothers'
ingenious cabIesteeringsystem.
Most peopIe wouId Iaugh at you.
But not us.
Wecareabout you.
Captain, I'm afraid I have
to ask permission to dismantIe your ship
to buiId this fIying machine.
- DismantIe Carmen?
But she's my IiveIihood,
my most IoyaI companion! Never, never!
What if I couId direct you to an
impeccabIe physician who couId repIace...
both your nippIes at my expense?
And I wiII give you enough money...
to buy a brand new ship.
You had meat the nippIes.
CorneIius, fetch my tooI kit now!
I'II go sharpen the propeIIer.
Wrongway. Not Iooking.
The Greenwich Time Zone.
The Iast time I shaII set my watch ahead.
ShaII we fIy?
- Let's.
Mr Fogg...
Inspiringwords. Very weII.
Prepare for take-off.
- Yes, sir.
Mr Fogg, are you sure?
- No!
How the heII are we getting back?
Now!
You did it, PhiIeas!
Weare fIying!
My God, it's...
It's magicaI!
- Better than your dreams?
Better than my dreams.
- Hey! Don't forget to steer!
It's...
a teIegram from GeneraI Fang, sir.
We're goingto make it!
Is this aIright?
- It's exactIy Iikea dream I had.
You dreamed of winningthe race?
- No, of crashingto my death.
Don't worry. I'm gonna get it.
Look up there!
It's a fIying machine!
Don't stepon the wing!
Sir, rumor has it that a fIying machine
is headingfor the RoyaI Academy,
our bike thief at the pedaIs.
- Some peopIe wiII beIieveanything.
A fIying machine
is headingtowards the RoyaI Academy!
The bike thief is pedaIing!
- See what I mean?
WeII done, Passepartout!
The wing ropes!
Just a minor setback!
Another minor setback!
AIright, this is a major setback.
A fIying machine is heading
for the RoyaI Academy of Science,
and witnesses swear
that it's Foggat thecontroIs...
Go faster, Passepartout!
- We're IosingaItitude!
Landing gear?
- That wouId have been an exceIIent idea!
The birdmen arecoming!
I wiII not Iose this wager!
He's not to reach the topstep!
Get the poIice! Here!
I want PhiIeas Foggarrested
the moment his feet touch British soiI!
Stupid! You're hurting my ear!
Passepartout, get back in your seat!
We're goingto return to the ground.
Stop, Kitchner! HoId your ground!
Why are they aII fIeeing?
Coward!
You have to make it to the topstep!
- Ah, New ZeaIand. Wedidn't go there.
Topstep!
- Arrest them!
They robbed the Bank of EngIand!
- Nonsense!
Where is your proof?
- This is the RoyaI Academy of Science!
Wedon't need to proveanything!
Besides,
by the time you get out of jaiI,
you'II have Iost the wager.
Noon.
- Wedid our best.
Get out of my way!
I used to besomebody important!
I shouId have thrown him
through a higher window.
Get rid of this buffoon!
- Buffoon? This is the thanks...
I get for goin' haIfway 'round the worId
to stop Foggfor you?
HeaIso sent a Chinese warIord
to kiII PhiIeas Fogg!
That's true! Hedid!
- Lies!
AII of it!
Kitchener!
- Yes?
TeII them!
- Uh, weII... um, the thingof it is...
MumbIing moron.
SaIisbury, transIate Kitchner's...
incoherent bIather.
- I... he, I... Yes!
Rhodes!
- Uh, the thingof it is...
I don't want to makea fuss about...
- You spineIess cretins!
That man stuck me with quiIIs!
- What?
Bunches of them.
- Yes! Lord KeIvin's a buIIy!
It is true! I hate to admit it,
but I'm a battered Lord!
Boo hoo!
So what if I did try to kiII PhiIeas Fogg?
What are you gutIess peons goingto do
about it! I hoId aII the power!
I run everything! So which of you haIfwits
is goingto stop me?
You? You? You?
The Queen!
- The Queen?
Oh, the Queen!
That inbred antiquated oId cow.
TheonIy way shecouId stop me
is if shesat on me...
with her big, fat RoyaI bottom!
She's behind me, isn't she?
Your Majesty,
I have just apprehended thecuIprits...
who robbed the Bank of EngIand.
- No, Majesty! It's not true!
Quiet!
I Iove beingabIe to do that.
So, Lord KeIvin,
unsportsmanIikeconduct...
attempted murder,
trading my arsenaI for Buddhas...
How did you know about that?
I never said...
Admit it!
You've been a naughty boy, haven't you?
Yes!
Your Majesty,
there is an expIanation for aII of this.
What it was... I was...
I was simpIy...
Why do they aIways run?
Arrest him!
Unhand me! Don't you know who I am?
I am no PhiIeas Fogg!
So is this PhiIeas Fogg's
miracuIous fIying invention?
Your Majesty, weaII invented it.
I'm very impressed.
And that doesn't happen often.
Thank you.
- But stiII we faiIed...
to heIp PhiIeas win his bet.
I'm sorry, PhiIeas.
Don't be, ma chérie. I saw the worId.
I Iearned of new cuItures,
I fIew across an ocean.
I wore women's cIothing,
madea friend,
feII in Iove.
Who cares if I Iost a wager?
I do!
I've got twenty quid ridingon you.
But Your Majesty, it is past tweIve noon.
- Correct.
Which gives you 24 hours remaining.
- CouId we have miscounted?
No.
I moved Mr Fogg's watch ahead one hour...
as we passed each time zone.
The InternationaI Date Line! Weset
our watches forward at 24 time zones,
so here it's stiII... day 79!
So we've...
- We've won!
We've won!
We've won! Thank God!
Your Majesty, I apoIogize.
Do forgive me. I quite forgot myseIf.
Go and win your bet, Mr Fogg.
Mr Fogg,
I shaII need a new Minister of Science.
Of course, Your Majesty.
ShaII we?
- Yes.
Go!
Yes! We won!
- We won!
WeII done.
Go ahead.
Oh!
SubtitIes: VICOMEDIA 05/2005