Yankee nine-niner,
what are your coordinates?
0-2-0.
Flight level 1-5.
Above release point
echo bravo one.
Move in
and check it out.
Roger.
Moving in.
Food riot in progress.
Approximately
1500 civilians.
No weapons evident.
Proceed with plan alpha.
Eliminate anything moving.
The crowd is unarmed.
There are lots
of women and children.
All they want is food!
Proceed with plan alpha.
All rioters must be eliminated.
The hell with you!
I will not fire
on helpless people.
Abort mission.
Return back to base.
Lieutenant Saunders,
take command.
Detain Richards.
Proceed as ordered.
Richards,
what are you doing?
AAah!
Damn it!
We're pitching over!
Ah!
I got it.
I got control.
He said detain him.
Don't drop him.
Ah!
Richards, you're
going to fry for this.
I'll see you
in hell.
Come on, keep digging.
What's the holdup?
This one's had it.
Watch the detonator.
Get that garbage
out of here.
Move!
Did you see
The Running Man
last night?
I never miss it.
I won 500 bucks.
Work crew
coming through.
Prisoner transfer
to post.
Ok, hang on.
Lenny, this is perimeter.
Shut down
the deadline.
Affirmative.
shutting down now.
Access code pending.
Verify perimeter
deactivated.
Sonic deadline is down.
OK, move it.
Move it.
Let's go, let's go.
Get out the lead
or lose your head.
East perimeter here.
New prisoners are
all in compound.
We're clear.
Affirmative.
Activating deadline.
What are you
looking at?
Get out of here!
Sonic deadline is up.
Prisoner restraint
Collars armed.
Yeah!
Give you a lift?
Get it open!
Repeat the codes.
I did. 653.
It's not working!
You're hell
of an actor, Laughlin.
Who was acting?
You're still alive,
aren't you?
Repeat that code.
Weiss, what's
the holdup?
Come on!
The linking computer
is denying the code.
Must be the walls in here
are blocking the signal.
We try it outside.
Let's go! come on!
Get out of the way!
Open the gates!
Go ahead, do it.
Shut off the deadline,
or we all lose our heads.
The system's blocked.
Must be a lock-out.
Damn!
Perimeter deactivated.
All right!
Chico! Amigo!
Chico! Come back!
The deadline's still up.
He's not going
to make it.
That collar's
going to blow.
Chico!
Sonic deadline.
Prisoner restraint collars
armed.
Perimeter deactivated.
Zone passes are required
at all times.
Display passes properly.
All interzone workers
with day passes
are reminded that curfew
begins at midnight.
Anyone without a valid
zone card after midnight
will be permanently detained.
Cadre kids,
Don't forget October is
bonus recruitment month.
Earn a double bonus
for reporting a family member.
ICS, your entertainment
and information network,
reminds you,
seeing is believing.
What's the number one
television show
in the whole wide world?
The Running Man!
Yes!
Yes, it's The Running Man.
400 square blocks of Danger,
destruction...
Psst!
You want to buy
a hot stereo?
Stevie.
Glad you guys
made it.
...unstoppable
network stalkers
give criminals, traitors,
and enemies of the state
exactly what they deserve.
Sundays, 8:00 to 11:00
on ICS channel 1.
Produced in cooperation
with the Department of Justice,
All rights reserved.
The Running Man,
America's favorite game show.
A child, your child-
happy, loving, caring...
do you
believe this?
24 hours a day.
Seven days a week.
Don't listen to it.
The network shuts
down the schools.
The kids
are brainwashed
By the TV.
We can
jam the network
Once we find
the satellite uplink.
We'll broadcast
the truth.
Truth? Hasn't been
popular lately.
Can't find the code
or the uplink
Don't know where
The network hid
something that big.
[beeping]
Steve, would you mind?
Good-bye, my lovely.
You're one of the cops
Who locked up
all my friends.
People like you
Turned this country
into a jail.
We don't want
his death
on our hands.
He's the Butcher
of Bakersfield.
Come on, Mic.
It's network
propaganda.
We wouldn't be here
if he hadn't helped us.
He's not
one of us.
Perhaps
he's seen too much.
All I've seen is a bunch
of low foreheads
Who think they can
change the world
with dreams and talk.
If you're not ready
to act, shut up.
Nothing worth losing
your head over, huh?
You got it.
Hey, get out
of here!
Well, there's
your ride.
It's all set.
Nothing like
first class.
Hey, senorita,
do you want to come in?
I guess this is it.
Now you, Weiss,
stay out
of the National
Data Base.
And you, Laughlin,
stop trying to teach
the constitution
to the street punks.
You can still
join us.
No, thank you.
I'm not into politics.
I'm into survival.
In our day,
it's the same thing.
Laughlin, save it
for the written test.
Yeah!
We need you,
Damon!
Brenda, do you have
this week's ratings,
or do I have
to guess?
They're the same
as last week.
Those were the same
last month.
We've peaked.
It's not like we dropped.
Whoa!
Sorry, Mr. Killian.
That's all right,
what's your name?
Dan.
You're doing
good work.
Thank you.
Brenda, if that asshole
is mopping tomorrow,
you'll be mopping
for the rest of the week.
Let's go!
Security code
accepted.
Edward?
Damon, were you
down in wardrobe yet?
Your new jackets
are fantastic.
Who chose the colors?
How are
my people today?
You're looking good.
Tony, what have you
got for me?
The Justice Department's
calling every 10 minutes.
Give them
an evasive answer.
Tell them to go
fuck themselves.
What have we got?
Lights.
Oh, God. Kitchen,
toast and coffee.
ICS Channel One.
Are you ready for pain?
Are you ready for suffering?
If the answer is yes,
Then you're ready
for Captain Freedom's workout.
Yes, it's America's own
Captain Freedom,
10-time national champion.
The greatest stalker
to ever play the game.
All right, all you runners,
Ready, get set, go!
We interrupt
Captain Freedom's workout
To bring you
this bulletin.
City police are engaged in
a door-to-door search
For Benjamin A. Richards,
the Butcher of Bakersfield.
Richards was
the helicopter pilot
who went berserk 18 months ago,
firing without warning
on a crowd
of innocent civilians.
If you see this man,
don't approach him.
Contact your local
block warden.
Don't make a sound.
Who are you?
A friend
of my brother's?
What are you
talking about?
This is
his apartment.
I moved in last month.
They told me
the last tenant
was taken away
for re-education.
Help!
Are you the man?
He's in my house!
The Butcher
of Bakersfield
Is in my bathroom!
That's the ticket.
no pain, no gain.
Let go of me!
Let me go!
Now, listen to me.
This is all a lie.
I was framed.
Yeah, sure.
Now be quiet.
Stay still.
I'm out of here
in five minutes.
Hi, this is Amber.
I'm not at home.
I'm out having
a wonderful time.
So when you hear the tone,
leave your message.
"Baby Face" march.
Are you kidding me?
Next!
How's this one?
Case 114.
Schoolteacher.
Killed his wife
and mother-in-law
at a faculty dinner.
I like that quality.
He's the sort
the neighbors say,
"Such a quiet man."
But look at him.
He weighs 120 pounds.
He wouldn't last
3o seconds.
Who else?
What about
those bank
robbers?
They made that
suicide pact.
Did they commit suicide?
Obviously not, Damon.
Then they're unreliable.
I got a friend
at a talent agency.
Hello, gorgeous.
Somebody with stamina.
Tony!
Pipe that feed
in here now.
Look at this.
This is yesterday's
prison break.
Look.
Look at that
mother move.
He's beautiful.
Who is he?
That's Ben Richards.
The cop
from the massacre?
Sensational!
I want him.
You can't have him.
Why not?
You know our contract.
We never get
military prisoners.
He's still
at large.
They'll get him
for me.
Cadres can't have it
both ways.
I can get 10 rating points
for his biceps alone.
Hello, this is Killian.
Get me the Justice
Department,
Entertainment Division.
No, hold that, operator.
Get me
the President's agent.
What is this?
That's my
synthesizer setup.
I'm a musician.
well, I'm really
a singer.
I wrote
the network's
theme song-
We bring you joy,
we bring you strife.
You must be
very proud of yourself.
It's really nothing.
Look at this.
They're all
on the censored list.
And look what
we have here.
This looks like
black-market clothing.
And you wrote
the network jingle.
Come on.
Everybody does it.
Money.
That's what I need.
Money's not going
to do you any good.
You don't have
a travel pass.
You do.
Now I do.
Now, let's see.
Now, where should we go?
Maybe someplace warm.
I need to work
on my tan anyway.
You get so pale
in prison.
There you are.
Good.
I'm going to untie you.
Then you're going to
get dressed.
You're coming with me.
Oh, Yeah.
Well, why should I?
Because I'm going
to say...
please.
Well...why didn't
you say so?
All flights to Pretoria,
Tutuville, and Mandelaburg
are on schedule.
Flights to Anaconda, Chile,
are delayed several hours.
All Mideast flights
are cancelled
until further notice.
You'll never
pull this off.
You are unarmed,
outnumbered.
Face it,
you're screwed.
So why don't you
forget about this
and turn
yourself in?
You know,
You have a very
negative attitude.
Remember, I can
break your neck
like a chicken's.
Travel pass.
What a beautiful
day today.
I can practically
taste those pina coladas.
Miss?
You didn't put it
in your purse again?
Last vacation she put
my credit cards
in there,
and we couldn't find them
for a week.
Move it up there!
Go on! Go on!
Can't live with them,
and you can't live
without them.
I'm warning you,
I get sick-
air sick, car sick.
I'm going to throw up
all over you.
Go ahead. It won't show
on this shirt.
Oow!
Help!
He's Ben Richards!
He's trying
to kidnap me!
Help!
Positive I.D.
Benjamin A. Richards.
Priority one fugitive.
All units, terminal seven.
All right.
We're on him.
Close the Net.
You move
and you're dead!
Hi, cutie pie.
One of us is
in deep trouble.
You know who I am?
I've seen you before.
You're the asshole on TV.
That's funny.
I was going to say
The same thing
about you.
I saw the video
of your prison break.
I think we can
help each other.
I've got the brains.
You've got talent.
You've got more.
You've got talent,
charisma,
That's why I pulled
a few strings
to get you here.
That's why
I'd like you
to volunteer to appear
on tomorrow's broadcast
of The Running Man.
Fuck you!
You're a brilliant
conversationalist, Ben.
A trifle limited,
but brilliant.
Take a look.
Isn't that your old
schoolteacher buddy?
There's your buddy
who helped you
in the prison
infirmary.
Weiss, Laughlin.
What are you going
to do with them?
Well, that's really
up to you, Ben.
You see, I created
The Running Man,
but I don't
make the rules.
I got a contract
with the government.
They send me convicts.
I put them on the show.
You know you've
got a chance,
but your buddies, Ben,
get the "B" list.
If you don't do
The Running Man
tomorrow,
Weiss and Laughlin
are going to go on
in your place.
What do you say?
We'll see how far
this clown runs
when we're done.
Starting Barium IV.
That's a go.
Reading all systems.
Your bird is singing
loud and clear.
All systems check out.
Mandibular restraint.
Interphalangic injection.
Deltoid I.M. injection.
Procedure completed.
Takes care of him.
Sons of bitches!
He's wrapped.
Knock him out
'til showtime.
Ugh!
Uhh!
These guys
never stop competing.
I get thirsty
just watching them.
I can't afford
that filled-up feeling.
That's why I drink
Cadre Cola.
It hits the spot.
The capture of renegade
police officer Ben Richards
was filmed yesterday
by runway security cameras.
Richards' hostage,
Amber Mendez,
was unharmed.
Some airport personnel
were not so lucky,
like the ticket agent
and security guard
Richards shot
at point-blank range.
But that's not true.
They're at
Cadre Memorial Hospital,
where they remain
in guarded condition.
And now, back to
climbing for dollars.
Yaah !
Mr. Richards.
I'm your court-appointed
theatrical agent.
It's time.
And digital effects
number one.
Roll process mod.
OK, you guys,
hey, here we are.
Come on, move! Move!
Big crowd tonight.
Better there
than in the streets.
Buzzsaw!
Who's your
number one stalker?
Hey, Buzzsaw!
slice those runners!
You guys see that?
Buzzsaw touched me!
Don't touch the hair!
Yeah!
Whoo!
Oh, Yeah!
Go!
Do you have
any more change?
I ran out.
$6.00.
This place-
you're lucky
to be alive.
That guy,
he's killed, what-
6o, 8o, 1oo people?
Not according to him,
he hasn't.
That's what
they all say.
"Whereas the victim
contests this,
"and whereas network
and victim
"have in past
been combatants
"ad hoc de facto,
"the parties herein
have agreed to disagree.
"This is mutually consented
to be de jure,
"and parties have certain
obligations to each other.
Respective rights
and obligations..."
Boy, lucky he didn't
kill you, too,
or rape you
and kill you,
or kill you,
then rape you.
"Conflicts
between your estate..."
I mean,
a guy like that...
what would stop him?
Yeah.
What would?
Look, Amy, I have to
pass on that drink.
I just remembered
I have some paperwork to do,
so I'll catch you
tomorrow, OK?
...and everyone's
favorite showman-
Damon Killian!
Yeah! Thank you!
You're beautiful!
I love you, Yes!
Thank you!
Ha ha!
Shh!
It's...
showtime!
Yeah, yeah!
All right!
Now, tell me.
What's the number-one
television show
in the whole wide world?
The Running Man!
Who loves you,
and who do you love?
Damon!
One more time!
Yes!
Phil, my announcer.
I heard the warm-up,
and I got to tell you,
honestly, Phil,
I don't think I've
ever heard you funnier.
I'm just kidding, guys.
You're great
at your job.
Too bad
it isn't music.
"...ad infinitum
"for cassettes,
videotapes, bubble chips,
and all other methods
of recordings known or unknown."
Sign here.
Hey!
Here, use
my back, victim.
Aah!
Don't forget
to send me a copy.
Aah!
The love of my life,
my number-one fan,
Mrs. Mcardle!
How you doin'?
Just fine.
I want
a big kiss, now,
but remember,
no tongues.
Bless you.
Sit down,
little darling.
We have one hell
of a show for you.
Phil, please,
if you will,
introduce tonight's
guest runner,
and watch that screen.
Our star runner tonight
needs no introduction.
he's Ben Richards,
the brutal slayer
of 60 men, women, and children
in the Bakersfield massacre.
Food riot in progress.
Approximately
1500 civilians.
Moving in.
The crowd is unarmed.
Repeat, unarmed.
Abort attack.
Acknowledge,
yankee nine-niner.
The hell with you.
Lieutenant Saunders,
take command.
Detain Richards
and return to base.
Acknowledge, yankee
nine-niner. Acknowledge!
Those are innocent,
unarmed people down there!
Cease fire! Cease fire!
Aah!
Oh!
Well, we all know
the aftermath-
grieving parents,
orphaned children,
a nation shocked
to its very core.
Here he is,
ready to pay the price
for our home audience,
in person,
the Butcher of Bakersfield!
Look!
Get him!
Boo! Boo!
Boo!
Now, Ben Richards
could have gone to prison,
but instead, he volunteered
for The Running Man.
Oh, excuse me.
...our fabulous prizes,
like a trial by jury,
suspended sentence,
maybe even a full pardon,
like our previous winners
Whitman, Price, and Haddad!
you remember them!
There they are!
At this very moment,
They're basking
under the Maui sun,
their debt to society
paid in full.
Speaking of prizes,
you don't have to be
a menace to society
to be a winner.
Phil, tell our friends
what they can win today.
Damon, how about
a year's supply
of Orthopure
procreation pills,
both adult
and kiddie sizes,
and the latest edition
of The Running Man home game.
Ben, I know
you're dying to show us
the same determination
you showed up in Bakersfield.
Well, first, I've got
a little surprise for you.
Ha ha ha!
We all know
you're a tough guy, Ben,
but that doesn't mean
you're a loner.
It takes a big man
to admit he needs friends.
We didn't want to break up
a winning team,
so here they are,
right by your side.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Ben's buddies,
Harold Weiss
and William Laughlin.
Son of a bitch!
You know how this works.
The game zone is divided
into 400 square blocks
left over from
the big quake of '97.
We will never forget that.
Once inside the zone,
runners have three hours to go
through all four game quads.
They'll need every second
because you know
who's on their tail?
The stalkers!
Who?
And you know
what happens then!
Anything goes!
What?
Right!
Without further ado,
it's time
to start running!
on your marks...
get set...
Killian...
I'll be back.
Only in a rerun.
Go!
Yes!
Ha ha ha!
Go, go, go!
"Edited for television."
"Raw footage."
Huh!
Edith Wiggins,
come on down!
Oh!
Yeah!
Ha ha ha!
Whoa, whoa, Edith.
You look like you've done
a little stalking yourself.
You give me
the name of the stalker
that we send out
to hunt down those criminals.
Give me
10 seconds, please.
Come on, come on.
Place your bets.
Dynamo, 3 to 1.
Time's up.
No more bets.
Back off!
Come on!
They're all so good.
Quickly!
My husband and son
have their favorites,
but I like my men
big and cuddly.
Subzero!
All right! OK!
We're looking
for Subzero!
Yeah!
And now, our first stalker
of the evening,
a cadre trophy champion
with over 30 lifetime kills,
let's welcome
the incredible iceman,
who slices his enemies
limb from limb
into quivering bloody sushi,
Professor Subzero!
Yeah!
Oh!
Yeeah!
Yaaah!
Let's go!
Come on!
Here in the locker room,
there's a lot of excitement,
a lot of adrenaline.
The stalkers know
there's 400 square blocks
of game zone,
and anything can happen
in the next three hours.
I remember once-
Sorry, cap.
I've just been informed
the runners
have entered the first quad.
Let's go there, live!
Faster!
Keep going!
Give it to me!
You pay your money,
you make your choice.
How about you?
It's cold.
What is this?
I guess
they want us to stay.
Subzero does it again!
A triple hit!
Let's get out of here!
Weiss, come on!
Go!
Aah!
Banzai!
Oh, look at this.
an ICS home video.
Yeah!
And The Running Man
home version
right here for you.
Get me out of here!
Hang on, Weiss.
I'm coming.
Eeah!
Ah!
Richards?
Will! Get me out
of here, you guys!
Will, look out!
Kill that son of a bitch !
Come on!
Come on! Yeah!
Aah!
Uugh!
Oh!
Hey, Killian!
Here is Subzero-
now plain zero.
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is just horrible.
Words can't express
what we're all feeling
at this very moment.
A great champion has fallen.
We'll be back right after
these important messages.
Pull!
You all right?
Yeah. Boy.
What the hell's that?
It's gas.
Let's get out
of here.
Sure glad we
took care of Subzero.
Yeah, he was a real
pain in the neck.
I know
a stalker died.
Well, it had to happen
sooner or later.
Yeah, well, it is
a contact sport, right?
Yes, you guys
at justice,
you cannot
have it both ways.
You want ratings,
you want people
in front of the TV sets
instead of picket lines-
well, you ain't
gonna get that
with reruns
of Gilligan's Island.
Gilligan's Island.
da da-da da
Yeah, the one with the boat.
Yeah, Buzzsaw!
Leon?
I think
maybe Dynamo, but...
but Buzzsaw was
last year's champion.
I can't decide.
Then don't
decide, Leon.
Hard decisions
call for hard solutions.
Here are two hard asses
ready to take charge.
You asked for them,
you got them.
Here they are-
Buzzsaw and Dynamo!
Phil, tell us all about
this champion tag team.
Let's give a down-home welcome
to Buzzsaw Eddie Vatowski,
last season's
leading stalker.
Buzzsaw's chain saws...
can cut muscle,
sinew, bone
or even solid steel!
The ratings jumped
eight points.
Make that
nine points.
I love Ben Richards.
Want another
surprise?
What?
Remember the girl
who was with Richards
at the airport?
With the cute ass?
They caught her
downstairs.
She was pulling
the Bakersfield video.
Sensational.
...Dynamo!
Thank you.
You're beautiful.
It's been
an exciting show so far.
We've had shocks,
we've had surprises.
We thought,
"why not one more surprise?"
Will you please
help me welcome
our mystery contestant-
Miss Amber Mendez!
Let me go!
Amber, now,
I understand
that you're
single, Amber,
and that you live
on the west side.
Not surprisingly,
she's flaunted the law
and traditional morality
all of her life.
Go ahead.
Tell some lies
about me now.
We don't lie.
Phil, tell us
all about her.
Weiss,
what is it?
The camera relay.
It's not pointing up.
Who gives a damn?
Hey, where
are you going?
Later, she cheated
on college exams,
had sexual relationships
with two, sometimes three
different men in a year,
and then she met
"mad dog" Ben Richards,
her confederate, her lover.
That was a lie!
Dear, dear, dear.
Let's reunite
these little lovebirds.
Go!
Aah!
It's got to
be here.
What is going on?
The relays
are the same.
They point into the middle
of the game zone.
The uplink
to the network satellite
is in there.
No wonder
Mic's people
couldn't find it.
If we find that uplink,
we can crack the code.
Jam the network.
Forget this
crazy business!
We got to
move on.
Let's go!
Move, move!
Christ!
Aah!
Stalkers,
we've got a bead-
20 degrees north,
mark 7,
12 degrees east, mark 2.
Come on, brothers!
Let's win one
for the zero!
"Uplinks.
Underground."
You guys
don't shut up,
I'm going to
uplink your ass.
You'll be underground!
Watch out! The lights!
Let's go!
Shh.
Someone's coming.
Richards, wait!
It's Amber!
What the hell
are you doing here?
You think I'm glad
to be here?
Who the hell is this?
She turned me in
at the airport.
This is her reward.
Well, go ahead.
Make jokes.
It's your fault
I'm here.
They even think
I'm your girlfriend.
See this camera up there?
I can strangle you
for the home audience.
Another relay.
Quick!
Weiss!
What's he
talking about?
Let's go.
Weiss, over here!
Richards! Look out!
You son of a bitch!
Richards, help!
Wait!
Laughlin, move it!
Yeah.
Let's go.
Give me your money.
OK. OK.
Hey, man, what
are you doing?
Hey!
The resistance wants to
jam the network.
Here's our chance.
Let's go!
No. This is
more important.
It's the uplink
to the network
satellite.
He's going to find us.
Weiss, come on.
Over there.
Hey!
Who loves you,
and who do you love?
Let me hear it.
You've got it.
Who loves you,
and who do you love?
Eyaa!
Laughlin!
Hang on, I've got you.
Run!
Get out of here!
Laughlin, get up!
Go! Go!
Go! Go! Go!
Eyaa!
Yah!
Aah!
There you go,
Leon.
Oh, wow!
Yeah!
The Running Man
home game.
Aah!
Let's get out of here.
He'll find us.
Jackpot!
What are you doing?
Weiss? What are
you doing?
What's this, Weiss?
It's the uplink interface.
Look out.
Great! Hexagonal
decode system.
Not impossible.
It'll just take
a little time.
Your name
is Amber, right?
Yeah.
Amber, I need you
to remember these numbers.
We've got to
get them to Mic.
Then let's Go!
Richards!
I love this saw.
This saw's part of me.
I'm gonna make it
part of you!
That's all right.
Keep it!
18, 24.
Come on.
61.
b.
Say them.
Say them!
18, 24, 61, b.
Can we go?
Not yet.
What do you mean?
17, 17.
4.
17, 7, 4.
17, 17, 4.
Come to me,
my love.
Oh, my God.
No!
Aah!
Let me Go!
Richards!
Hey!
Light head!
Hey, christmas tree!
Richards!
Ahh.
Yaa!
Yay!
Yeah! Get him!
Yeah!
All right!
Follow me, light bulb!
Ah, got you!
Come on!
All right!
Oh, God.
I'm stuck!
Somebody help me!
God, cut!
Go to commercials.
Jesus Christ!
I have no power.
Go to commercial!
Kill him!
No. I won't kill
a helpless human being,
Not even sadistic scum
like you.
Oh, my God!
Boo!
Come on!
Do it!
What happened
to Buzzsaw?
He had
to split.
Boo!
Hey, what
an incredible battle!
Buzzsaw gone,
Dynamo down,
but the stalk
isn't over
'til the fat lady sings,
and the very
last criminal...
Fireball, report
to wardrobe at once.
Fireball,
you're wanted in wardrobe.
And our halftime show!
Laughlin,
break's over.
Come on.
Let's get going.
I'm going somewhere,
but not with you.
Buzzsaw took
care of my...
Traveling
arrangements.
Oh, my God.
Weiss?
He is dead.
Ohh...
But he gave me
the code,
the satellite
uplink code.
The underground has
a broadcast center
in quadrant four.
Take her. Take her
and the code to Mic.
Don't let us die
for nothing.
Listen, we're
counting on you.
Don't let us down.
I don't want to be
the only asshole
in heaven
Ben.
He saved my life.
It should be me
down there.
We got them?
Hey, Ben?
I got to hand
it to you, pal.
You got the whole network
in an uproar.
They're shipping bicarb
to the Justice Department
in crates.
This call is
between us.
It's not on the air.
Listen carefully, Ben.
How would you like
a three-year contract,
guaranteed,
a cadre credit line,
and a beach-front condo?
Sound impossible?
Ben, that's
the standard deal
for a network stalker.
I know real talent.
I'd hate to see you
get canceled tonight
when you could
go the distance.
Say the word, Ben.
You could be
doing the stalking.
What do you think?
You cold-blooded
bastard.
I'll live to see
you eat that contract.
Leave room for my fist
because I'll ram it
into your stomach
and break
your goddamn spine!
Damon,
it's for you.
W-who?
It's the attorney
general.
Get out.
Everybody, out.
Come on.
Move.
Yes.
Fireball! Fireball!
Come on, Fireball.
Yay!
Let's go!
He's my hero!
Fireball!
There he goes.
Fireball's
on his way.
Dynamo's down,
but not out.
Back to you, Damon.
All right, Agnes.
Big chance.
Win lots of prizes.
We've still got
two crack stalkers-
Dynamo and Fireball.
Who will make
the next kill?
Oh, boy.
That's
a tough one.
Give it a try.
who do you think?
OK.
I think
the next kill
will be
made by...
Ben Richards.
Hold it.
Agnes, Richards
is a runner.
You've got
to pick a stalker.
I can pick
anyone I choose,
and I choose...
Ben Richards.
Richards?
He's one mean
motherfucker.
$200 on Richards!
Come on!
200 on Richards!
$200 on Richards!
Come on-
Just do it?
Just do it.
OK. OK.
You want it.
You got it.
Place your bet.
Secret broadcast center
doesn't exist.
There's nothing out here.
We should have
taken that trip
to Hawaii.
I had the shirt,
but you fucked it up.
Jesus Christ!
Guess again.
Come on, keep up.
I'm running
too fast.
My feet can't keep up!
There he goes,
the number-one rusher.
he smells blood,
and nothing on earth
can stop him.
Wait. I don't
Want to go.
Richards!
Here. This way.
Why? I want
to go that way.
Let go of me.
Put me down.
You're going
to get us killed.
Aah! Stop it!
Richards!
Let me Go!
Amber, get
out of here.
Go! Now!
Richards!
Amber!
Richards.
Aah!
Whitman.
and Price.
Haddad.
They're Running Men.
Last season's winners.
No.
Last season's
losers.
Huh?
Aah!
Why can't I fly?
How about a light?
Aah!
What a hothead.
Yeah, Richards!
Captain Freedom
to wardrobe
on the double.
Forget it, Killian.
I won't do it.
It's no request,
It's an order.
I don't need this crap.
This stuff is...
garbage!
I-
I used to kill
guys like this
with my hands.
I'm not using
any tricks.
This is a sport
of death and honor.
Code of
the gladiators!
Spare me the combat
zen speech.
What's the matter
with you?
Can't you see
what's going on?
This isn't a game!
They're betting on
Richards up there!
Bullshit!
Get out of here.
Get him
out of here!
What's the matter?
Steroids
make you deaf?
Get him out
of here now!
Now what?
Let's find Mic's
secret broadcast center,
if it even exists.
Oh, shit!
Let's try that way.
We're trapped.
Subzero,
Fireball,
and Buzzsaw.
Say their names
with reverent pride.
They punished crime
and served the law.
As patriots,
they died.
I hate
third-act problems.
Roll...
stock.
Freeze in
digital memory.
and...
activate
traveling matte.
Tony,
this better work,
or you'll be
a digital memory.
Take it easy,
Damon.
We're loading
Richards' image
onto the data base.
When he's mapped
onto the stunt double,
you'll never
know the difference.
All right, boys.
Let's see you dance.
Sensational.
I love it!
Mr. Richards,
you're so easily caught.
Welcome
to the people's network.
We've been
waiting for you.
This is nice, Mic,
but you could've
gotten off your asses
and helped us.
We'd have been seen.
The government
would have found us.
Laughlin, Weiss
would have died
for nothing.
They didn't.
I have
the uplink code.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I've got an update
on tonight's
incredible action.
The runners have entered
the final quad.
Captain Freedom has hung up
his announcer's mike
and come out
of retirement.
He's ready for
the final conflict.
Let's go now, live,
to the game zone!
Aah!
Uh!
Ha ha ha!
Yes, it's all over!
What a colossal fight!
This is an incredible
moment in sports.
Captain Freedom, out of
retirement and undefeated-
proving that right and might are one and the same!
Damn that Killian!
You should be happy.
We're officially dead.
We can do anything.
Don't you understand?
They'll never
let us out alive.
They can't afford it.
They'll hunt us down.
Off camera, of course.
OK. Dismantle
all the overlays.
Put
the digital matte
in the pixel
memory storage.
The damn thing
worked like a charm.
It should.
Editel charged us
an arm and a leg
for the software.
Damon! You didn't
have to kill him!
It's part
of life, Brenda.
You better fuckin'
get used to it.
That's one for
the award show.
Thank you.
You're doing nice work.
Tony, you're
finally getting it.
You don't need guns
to jam a satellite.
I do,
to keep it.
The network
will try to shunt
the next signal
in orbit.
Stevie's group
will stop them.
These kids?
This is
a bad move, Mic.
They need a leader,
Someone
with experience.
I thought you were
looking for the door.
I told Killian
I'd be back.
I wouldn't want
to be a liar.
listen up,
everybody.
I want you all
to consider
yourselves
picked up
for the rest
of the season.
Are you my people
or an oil painting?
We're up nine points.
Come on, now.
Let's go, champ.
We're going to send
the uplink code
in 20 minutes.
10 seconds later,
I'll go on the air.
We'll be ready.
If you want to
make an impression,
forget the speech.
Try this instead.
What is it?
The original video
from the Bakersfield
massacre
before they edited
for broadcasting.
Where did you
hide that?
It's none
of your business.
Hey,
what the hell-uh!
Six minutes.
Begin satellite
coding sequence.
Load uplink code into
transponder grid.
Shunt power
to main circuits.
Mr. Spock,
you have the com.
Who's Mr. Spock?
Come on.
Let me hear it now.
Whoo! Whoo!
Welcome to the postgame
wrap-up show.
Ladies,
I loved you.
Thank you,
young man.
Hello, you're
on the air.
Hi, Damon.
I'm Wendy.
I have a question
about Dynamo.
Is he seriously hurt?
He'll be fine.
Good luck.
He's under
factory warranty.
You, too.
You're on the air.
I feel bad about
the dead stalkers.
May I make a donation
to their families?
What a darling.
Send your checks
to the patriot's fund,
care of this station-
3,
2,
1.
That's it.
We got that baby!
Those contributions
are tax deductible.
Who loves you,
and who do you love?
Damon!
Yes!
Hey, what's
going on?
We don't lie...
like our
previous winners,
Whitman, Price,
and Haddad.
There they are,
at this very moment,
basking under the Maui sun,
their debt to society
paid in full.
Watch...
that screen.
yankee nine-niner.
What's
the crowd's status?
Food riot in progress.
Approximately
1500 civilians.
No weapons evident.
Proceed with plan alpha.
Eliminate anything moving.
The crowd is unarmed.
There are lots
of women and children.
All they want is food!
Proceed with plan alpha.
All rioters must be eliminated.
I won't fire
at helpless people.
Where's it coming from?
The network
satellite.
Abort mission.
Return to base.
Don't touch that dial.
Detain Richards.
Proceed as ordered.
Richards, what
are you doing?
Ladies and gentlemen!
Please bear with us!
We're experiencing
technical difficulties!
Bullshit!
It's showtime!
Get the people out!
Come on!
Huh!
Uhh!
Thought it was funny
out in the zone.
What's
the matter now?
Why aren't you laughing?
Because there's nothing funny
about a dickless moron
with a battery
up his ass!
Uhh!
Out! Out!
I'll show you
dickless!
Aah! Oh! Oh!
Oh! Oh!
Aah! Aah!
Get out of the way!
Get down! Down!
Aah!
Go!
Hello, cutie pie.
One of us
is in deep trouble.
Ha ha ha!
Sven, do you
want to talk
to Mr. Richards?
Well?
I got to score
some steroids.
You look pissed, Ben.
Believe me,
you got every right to be.
But will you
let me explain?
This is television.
It's nothing to do
with people.
It's ratings.
For 50 years,
we've told them what to eat,
what to drink,
what to wear.
Ben, don't you
understand?
Americans
love television.
They wean
their kids on it.
They love game shows,
they love wrestling.
They love sports
and violence.
So what do we do?
We give them
what they want!
We're
number one, Ben.
That's
all that counts.
Believe me.
I've done this
for 30 years.
I haven't been
in show business
as long as you have,
but I'm giving
the audience
what I think
they want.
Aah!
Ooh!
You bastard!
Drop dead!
I don't do requests.
No!
Aaaahhhhh!
Well, that hit the spot.
Yeah!
Yah hah!
Yee hah!
All right! Yeah!
Richards! Richards!
Richards! Richards! Richards!
This is no game
standing in the dark
I swear I heard you
calling my name
and I knew
things had changed
no pain, no gain
somethin' in your eyes
just told me
that this nightmare would end
and I had found a friend
shout it
from the highest steeple
let it out
to all the people
you hit the right spot
no more lonely nights
with a restless heart
roll the dice
make a brand-new start
when the world you knew
got shattered
you and me
were all that mattered
just one way I'm gonna lose
this restless heart
runnin' away with you
human again
I take you in my arms
and hold you
'til the fear is all gone
and now the race is won
shout it
from the highest steeple
let it out
to all the people
hey!
Scream it
on the loudest speaker
burnin'
like the highest fever
you hit the right spot
no more lonely nights
with a restless heart
roll the dice
make a brand-new start
when the world you knew
got shattered
you and me
were all that mattered
just one way I'm gonna lose
this restless heart
runnin' away with you
there's a new horizon
that we're both heading to
it's out there
in the distance
and it's playin' our tune
restless heart
runnin' away with you
human again
I take you in my arms
and hold you
'til the fear is all gone
and now the race is won
shout it
from the highest steeple
let it out
to all the people
hey!
Scream it
on the loudest speaker
burnin'
like the highest fever
you hit the right spot
no more lonely nights
with a restless heart
roll the dice
make a brand-new start
when the world you knew
got shattered
you and me
were all that mattered
just one way I'm gonna lose
this restless heart
runnin' away with you
roll the dice
make a brand-new start
runnin' away
runnin' away with you
with a restless heart
The Running Man
has been brought to you by
breakaway
paramilitary uniforms,
Orthopure procreation pill,
and Cadre Cola-
it hits the spot.
promotional considerations
paid for by
Kelton Flame Throwers,
Wainwright
Electrical Launchers,
and Hammond and Gage
chain saws.
Damon Killian's wardrobe
by Chez Antoine,
19th-century craftsmanship
for the 21st-century man.
cadre trooper
and studio guard sidearms
provided by Colchester,
the pistol of patriots.
tickets for the ICS studio tour
are always available
for class "A" citizens
in good standing.
if you'd like
to be a contestant
on The Running Man,
send a self-addressed
stamped envelope
to ICS talent hunt,
care of your local affiliate,
and then go and do something
really despicable.
I'm Phil Hilton.
good night and take care.